<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	
	<title type="text" xml:lang="en"></title>
	<link type="application/atom+xml" href="http://troy.yort.com/feed/" rel="self"/>
  <link type="text" href="http://troy.yort.com/" rel="alternate"/>
	<updated>2017-10-22T11:47:35-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://troy.yort.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name></name>
  </author>
  <rights> is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License.</rights>
  <updated>2017-10-22T11:47:35-07:00</updated>
	
	
	<entry>
		<title>Questions to ask before joining a startup</title>
    <link href="http://troy.yort.com/questions-to-ask-before-joining-a-startup/"/>
		<updated>2017-10-22T11:16:16-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://troy.yort.com/questions-to-ask-before-joining-a-startup</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A friend asked what I&amp;rsquo;d want to know about a startup, even a late-stage one, in order to better evaluate a job offer. Here&amp;rsquo;s the short list of less-obvious questions I&amp;rsquo;d ask before joining a startup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;The role&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you could make one impact in the business in your first 6-12 months, what what would it be (according to them)? This is as much to understand the metric they chose &amp;ndash; revenue? product usage? features shipped? employees hired? &amp;ndash; and why it&amp;rsquo;s important as it is to understand the amount.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where do you see the company in 3 years? What internal or industry changes might make you cut the vision short or significantly change the goal?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is there an employee who everyone thinks of as very connected and savvy, who you could use as a mentor for a few months to learn the communication style? If you&amp;rsquo;re remote, ideally this person will be too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h4&gt;The offer&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get enough understanding of the company&amp;rsquo;s cap table to have an idea what your offer represents. At a minimum, ask what percent of the shares currently outstanding your options would be, if they were vested.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What happens to vested options if you leave. Have they solved &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessinsider.com/pinterest-will-let-employees-exercise-options-for-seven-years-after-leaving-2015-3&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=9253497&quot;&gt;problem&lt;/a&gt;? If not, it dramatically decreases the value of the options; you basically have to stay until IPO (or some resale event) or acquisition, or take a risk that few people would (exercise illiquid options), or leave with no shares. 7 years is a reasonable length. 3 years is not awful. Given how long companies remain private, 1 year or less is insane; those options are basically toys.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h4&gt;Meta&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is the company forthcoming with the answers? Best case: the company not only answers the questions thoroughly, but also gives detailed reasoning behind their answers. If it seems like they&amp;rsquo;re reluctant to answer (or worse, dismissive of your need to know), that may be a hint how important employees&amp;#8217; concerns are, how much they&amp;rsquo;ve thought about the role you&amp;rsquo;d be doing, or how savvy other recent new employees are.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>If Yelp put quality above quantity…</title>
    <link href="http://troy.yort.com/if-yelp-put-quality-above-quantity-dot-dot-dot/"/>
		<updated>2016-07-29T11:09:35-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://troy.yort.com/if-yelp-put-quality-above-quantity-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I posted &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=12188315&quot;&gt;this comment&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=12184688&quot;&gt;this Hacker News thread&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Yelp put accuracy and completeness ahead of # of reviews, they&amp;rsquo;d have already made 2 changes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let anyone comment on other people&amp;rsquo;s comments &amp;ndash; like HN or Reddit, with similar reputation (points) and up/downvotes.
 Right now, unless an owner monitors and responds to every negative comment, there&amp;rsquo;s no recourse for being unreasonable or flat-out inaccurate. Even when an owner does so, the recourse is minimal. Let any other Yelp user reply, turning each comment into a thread.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When someone posts a 1- or 2-star review, show a second, required comment field for &amp;ldquo;What happened when you informed the retailer?&amp;rdquo;
 If someone is served a meal they don&amp;rsquo;t like and says nothing at the time, they skipped a &amp;ndash; the &amp;ndash; critical step. While there are cases where a low review could be justified without ever giving the retailer a chance to address the perceived problem (like if someone showed up twice during posted business hours and the retailer was closed), they cause fewer than 10% of 1- and 2-star ratings and they&amp;rsquo;re easy to explain. Otherwise, the minimum for a negative review to be constructive is having informed the retailer (and let them try to address it).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>FastMail as &#8220;customer or consumer?&#8221; experiment</title>
    <link href="http://troy.yort.com/fastmail-as-customer-or-consumer-experiment/"/>
		<updated>2015-11-16T10:07:23-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://troy.yort.com/fastmail-as-customer-or-consumer-experiment</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I posted &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=10575488&quot;&gt;this comment&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=10572597&quot;&gt;FastMail: Shutting down our XMPP service&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Background: A &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=10572819&quot;&gt;comment&lt;/a&gt;
criticized people for wanting to be &amp;ldquo;consumers&amp;rdquo; instead of &amp;ldquo;customers.&amp;rdquo;
Many other comments implied that people should want to pay for service received
and/or to encourage interoperability. That&amp;rsquo;s a fine opinion, but not when
concurrently using Google because it&amp;rsquo;s free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the comment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When someone raises this concern, I ask who hosts their personal email. 30-50% use a legacy free Google Apps account or Gmail. When I ask why, it&amp;rsquo;s a variation on &amp;ldquo;because FastMail &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastmail.com/help/ourservice/pricing.html&quot;&gt;costs&lt;/a&gt; ~$40/year.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of the rest, more than half host their own MX. While that&amp;rsquo;s totally reasonable, it means the percentage of people willing to pay just $3/month to be a customer is even smaller than it seems. And $40/year is the cheapest that one could ever hope &amp;ldquo;being a customer&amp;rdquo; would cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, lots of people say they want to be customers, but even when doing so is close to free, very few actually do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Nothing wrong with using Google because it&amp;rsquo;s free, only while concurrently claiming to want to be a customer. I agree with your point and I&amp;rsquo;m a happy FastMail customer. I&amp;rsquo;m amazed FastMail can make a profit at $40 and it&amp;rsquo;s a huge credit to them that they can.)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Comment on: How do I stop comparing myself to others?</title>
    <link href="http://troy.yort.com/comment-on-how-do-i-stop-comparing-myself-to-others/"/>
		<updated>2015-11-08T07:52:11-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://troy.yort.com/comment-on-how-do-i-stop-comparing-myself-to-others</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I posted a &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=10528744&quot;&gt;comment&lt;/a&gt; on the
Hacker News thread &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=10523788&quot;&gt;Ask HN: How do I stop comparing myself to others?&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Society didn&amp;rsquo;t offer &amp;ldquo;Start a geek-centric Web service, then spend years
quietly building it profitably, and do so while living in a dozen different
cities&amp;rdquo; as a viable journey, let alone a valuable goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the comment:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find a goal or even a yardstick that&amp;rsquo;s more meaningful to you than to anyone else. Ideally, also find a path to it that&amp;rsquo;s uniquely appealing to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s way harder to think about what you want than to hop on to society&amp;rsquo;s defaults (schools, work prestige, wealth, looks, ..). &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.paulgraham.com/love.html&quot;&gt;http://www.paulgraham.com/love.html&lt;/a&gt; touches on this (&amp;ldquo;if you admire two kinds of work equally, [choose the less prestigious]&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When no one else is trying to accomplish the same thing in the same way, only absolute measurements matter: how close did you get? How much did you enjoy the ride?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Papertrail joins SolarWinds and accelerates growth</title>
    <link href="http://troy.yort.com/papertrail-joins-solarwinds-and-accelerates-growth/"/>
		<updated>2015-04-28T09:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://troy.yort.com/papertrail-joins-solarwinds-and-accelerates-growth</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;(This post was actually published on July 23, 2016 when I realized that the
draft was never published)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m thrilled that Papertrail is now part of SolarWinds. Here&amp;rsquo;s more:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.papertrailapp.com/papertrail-joins-solarwinds-and-accelerates-growth/&quot;&gt;Papertrail joins SolarWinds and accelerates growth&lt;/a&gt; on papertrailapp.com&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.solarwinds.com/company/newsroom/press_releases/solarwinds_adds_cloud_based_log_management_acquisition_of_papertrail.aspx&quot;&gt;SolarWinds Adds Cloud-based Log Management Capabilities with Acquisition of Papertrail&lt;/a&gt; on solarwinds.com&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Notes on standing desk</title>
    <link href="http://troy.yort.com/notes-on-standing-desk/"/>
		<updated>2015-01-04T16:14:55-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://troy.yort.com/notes-on-standing-desk</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I posted a bit about my first 6 weeks with a standing desk on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/philg/2015/01/03/standing-and-treadmill-desk-ideas-and-experience/comment-page-1/#comment-260561&quot;&gt;Philip
Greenspun&amp;rsquo;s blog&lt;/a&gt;. The post is below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bought both a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.geekdesk.com/geekdesk-max-frame-only&quot;&gt;GeekDesk Max&lt;/a&gt; frame and an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thehumansolution.com/uplift-920-electric-sit-stand-no-crossbar-desk-base-black.html&quot;&gt;Uplift 920&lt;/a&gt;. The 920 has a removable section of the desk mount so it can accept a full-depth keyboard drawer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I kept the Uplift and after 2 months, am thrilled with it. They&amp;rsquo;re both excellent products and incredible values. I opted for the Uplift because of the removable section, a longer warranty, no back brace between the legs (leaves room for bike or taller treadmill), and a design which allows the controls to be mounted anywhere. I don&amp;rsquo;t see any difference in sturdiness or daily use. The motor on the Uplift is slightly faster, but it makes no difference. I mounted an IKEA Numerar solid butcher block on it, mostly because just about all desktops on the market are deeper than the ~24&amp;#8221; I wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of adjustable standing desks are actually rebranded legs, controls, and control boxes from a company called LINAK: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.linak.com/products/lifting-columns.aspx?sbaid=2&quot;&gt;LINAK&lt;/a&gt;. Other than the very high-end office furniture makers, I&amp;rsquo;d guess more than half of electric adjustable desks are from LINAK VARs (GeekDesk and THS included): &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.linak.com/deskline/&quot;&gt;LINAK Deskline&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I know how to spot them, I see Uplifts everywhere. The standing desk photo in &lt;a href=&quot;http://tmagazine.blogs.nytimes.com/2014/11/13/olafur-eliasson-interview-fondation-louis-vuitton/&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; is the Uplift or identical components.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with the desk, buy a large CumulusPRO mat: &lt;a href=&quot;http://thewirecutter.com/reviews/best-standing-desk-mat/&quot;&gt;The Wirecutter&lt;/a&gt;. A quality anti-fatigue mat is not optional. I also use a Kinesis &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kinesis-ergo.com/shop/freestyle2-for-mac/&quot;&gt;Freestyle&lt;/a&gt; split keyboard and Evoluent &lt;a href=&quot;http://evoluent.com/&quot;&gt;VerticalMouse&lt;/a&gt;. Typing and mousing feel like extending my arms forward. Otherwise, just listen to your body. If you&amp;rsquo;re exhausted or something hurts, sit down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have no firsthand experience with a treadmill desk. Our accountant uses a treadmill desk and has for years. He &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/papertrailapp/status/452162788547239936&quot;&gt;swears by&lt;/a&gt; it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bought my desk intending to add either a treadmill or a bike. Last week, I ordered a bike because I wanted to also use it for full-energy cycling (while not working or barely occupied). It&amp;rsquo;s essentially &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thehumansolution.com/uplift-spin-bike.html&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;, only with a belt drive Sunny SF-B1002 flywheel bike instead of the chain drive Marcy bike in the photo.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Improve Linux tcp_tw_recycle man page entry</title>
    <link href="http://troy.yort.com/improve-linux-tcp-tw-recycle-man-page-entry/"/>
		<updated>2014-11-23T09:01:38-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://troy.yort.com/improve-linux-tcp-tw-recycle-man-page-entry</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We recently identified the cause of a problem affecting one of
&lt;a href=&quot;https://papertrailapp.com&quot;&gt;Papertrail&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; service providers. Their hosts
occasionally could not establish TCP connections with a seemingly-random
small set of Internet hosts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Troubleshooting was difficult because:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The affected hosts changed. One host would oscillate between being able to establish a connection for a
few hours (or days) and not, seemingly with no pattern.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t have direct access to the service provider&amp;rsquo;s hosts or the end
users&amp;#8217; hosts. This made reproducing the problem in a controlled environment
basically impossible. &amp;ldquo;Paste the output of..&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Run this packet capture..&amp;rdquo;
was what I had to work with.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t draw conclusions from the end users who reported the problem.
Fewer than 5 users reported problems and they were biased towards inquisitive
people (who investigated or reported the first occurrence) or those who
experienced the problem multiple times. Presumably, some end users couldn&amp;rsquo;t
connect once and just tried again later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Among this tiny pool, there was one common theme: the remote hosts traversed
NAT. My investigation eventually led to &lt;code&gt;tcp_tw_recycle&lt;/code&gt;, a Linux &lt;code&gt;sysctl&lt;/code&gt; flag
with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=tcp_tw_recycle&quot;&gt;far more Google results&lt;/a&gt;
than it deserves. Here&amp;rsquo;s why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Linux TCP header verification&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Modern Linux kernels verify that TCP header values meet certain requirements.
These include &amp;ldquo;Protect Against Wrapped Sequence numbers&amp;rdquo; or PAWS, defined in
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ietf.org/rfc/rfc1323.txt&quot;&gt;RFC 1323&lt;/a&gt;, and
&lt;a href=&quot;https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc6191&quot;&gt;RFC 6191&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ldquo;Reducing the TIME-WAIT State
Using TCP Timestamps.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With &lt;code&gt;tcp_tw_recycle&lt;/code&gt; enabled, a connection&amp;rsquo;s TCP header timestamp value is
retained in cases where it otherwise would not have been kept. From
&lt;a href=&quot;https://git.kernel.org/cgit/linux/kernel/git/stable/linux-stable.git/tree/net/ipv4/tcp_ipv4.c?h=linux-2.6.32.y#n200&quot;&gt;tcp_ipv4.c&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#39;code&#39;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;gutter&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;line-numbers&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;11&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;12&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;13&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;14&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;15&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&#39;code&#39;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#39;&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;if (tcp_death_row.sysctl_tw_recycle &amp;&amp;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;    !tp-&amp;gt;rx_opt.ts_recent_stamp &amp;&amp; rt-&amp;gt;rt_dst == daddr) {
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;        struct inet_peer *peer = rt_get_peer(rt);
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;        /*
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;         * VJ&#39;s idea. We save last timestamp seen from
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;         * the destination in peer table, when entering state
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;         * TIME-WAIT * and initialize rx_opt.ts_recent from it,
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;         * when trying new connection.
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;         */
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;        if (peer != NULL &amp;&amp;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;            peer-&amp;gt;tcp_ts_stamp + TCP_PAWS_MSL &amp;gt;= get_seconds()) {
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;                tp-&amp;gt;rx_opt.ts_recent_stamp = peer-&amp;gt;tcp_ts_stamp;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;                tp-&amp;gt;rx_opt.ts_recent = peer-&amp;gt;tcp_ts;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;        }
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The problem: the TCP timestamp is only tracked on a per-remote-IP basis, yet
some NAT devices don&amp;rsquo;t rewrite TCP timestamps in the translation process.
As a result, the Internet-facing IP of a NAT device may transmit valid packets
with unrelated timestamps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem we saw manifests when more than one remote host (for example, two
employees on an office network) try to connect to this Linux host within a few
minutes of one another. The first connection will succeed, but the
second connection attempt (from the same public NAT IP) will fail. The
kernel considers its timestamp invalid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In another function, a comment hints at the difference between tracking
timestamps on a per-host basis and doing so on a per-port-pair basis. From
&lt;a href=&quot;https://git.kernel.org/cgit/linux/kernel/git/stable/linux-stable.git/tree/net/ipv4/tcp_ipv4.c?h=linux-2.6.32.y#n112&quot;&gt;tcp_ipv4.c&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#39;code&#39;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;gutter&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;line-numbers&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&#39;code&#39;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#39;&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;/* With PAWS, it is safe from the viewpoint
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;   of data integrity. Even without PAWS it is safe provided sequence
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;   spaces do not overlap i.e. at data rates &amp;lt;= 80Mbit/sec.
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;   Actually, the idea is close to VJ&#39;s one, only timestamp cache is
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;   held not per host, but per port pair and TW bucket is used as state
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;   holder.
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;   If TW bucket has been already destroyed we fall back to VJ&#39;s scheme
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;   and use initial timestamp retrieved from peer table.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Note: I haven&amp;rsquo;t read anywhere near all of Linux&amp;rsquo;s TCP header source. If you
find an error in this post, let me know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Root cause&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although that&amp;rsquo;s the problem, the root cause is poor documentation. The two
places that a systems administrator is most likely to consult are
the kernel &lt;a href=&quot;https://git.kernel.org/cgit/linux/kernel/git/stable/linux-stable.git/tree/Documentation/networking/ip-sysctl.txt?h=linux-2.6.32.y#n438&quot;&gt;IP sysctl docs&lt;/a&gt;, which suggests consulting &amp;ldquo;technical experts&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#39;code&#39;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;gutter&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;line-numbers&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&#39;code&#39;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#39;&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;tcp_tw_recycle - BOOLEAN
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;        Enable fast recycling TIME-WAIT sockets. Default value is 0.
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;        It should not be changed without advice/request of technical
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;        experts.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;.. and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://man7.org/linux/man-pages/man7/tcp.7.html&quot;&gt;tcp.7 man page&lt;/a&gt;, which says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#39;code&#39;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;gutter&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;line-numbers&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&#39;code&#39;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#39;&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;tcp_tw_recycle (Boolean; default: disabled; since Linux 2.4)
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;        Enable fast recycling of TIME_WAIT sockets.  Enabling this
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;        option is not recommended since this causes problems when
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;        working with NAT (Network Address Translation).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Neither of these explain what the option changes or how it interacts with
NAT. I&amp;rsquo;ve submitted &lt;a href=&quot;http://marc.info/?l=linux-man&amp;amp;m=141676013318902&amp;amp;w=2&quot;&gt;a patch&lt;/a&gt;
for the man page. The changed copy warns of the possible impact and says
where to learn more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Enable fast recycling of TIME_WAIT sockets. Enabling this option is
not recommended for devices communicating with the general Internet
or using NAT (Network Address Translation). Since some NAT gateways
pass through IP timestamp values, one IP can appear to have
non-increasing timestamps. See RFC 1323 (PAWS), RFC 6191.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s also a 2013 &lt;a href=&quot;https://tools.ietf.org/html/draft-penno-behave-rfc4787-5382-5508-bis-04#section-3.1.2&quot;&gt;BCP&lt;/a&gt;
(&amp;ldquo;Network Address Translation Behavioral Requirements Updates&amp;rdquo;)
which informs future NAT implementors of this consideration.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Clearer permission message for Chrome new tab extensions</title>
    <link href="http://troy.yort.com/clearer-permission-message-for-chrome-new-tab-extensions/"/>
		<updated>2014-08-16T10:38:02-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://troy.yort.com/clearer-permission-message-for-chrome-new-tab-extensions</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In creating Taco&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://tacoapp.com/chrome&quot;&gt;Chrome extension&lt;/a&gt;, I
became familiar with Chrome&amp;rsquo;s permission system. An extension defines
the information it accesses, like request history, and Chrome shows
permission-specific descriptions to end users when they try to install
it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently added the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.chrome.com/extensions/topSites&quot;&gt;topSites&lt;/a&gt; permission
to Taco&amp;rsquo;s extension, which grants very limited access: the URLs and page
titles of the 20 most frequently visited sites. It&amp;rsquo;s the information
shown on Chrome&amp;rsquo;s new tab page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I added this permission, here&amp;rsquo;s what Chrome presented to users (as
reported by a justifiably surprised user):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tacoapp&quot;&gt;@tacoapp&lt;/a&gt; The reason I ask is that it states on your website that the extension &amp;#39;can&amp;#39;t access your browsing data&amp;#39;… &lt;a href=&quot;http://t.co/9EUFn4TrW5&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/9EUFn4TrW5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Adam Sait (@adamsait) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/adamsait/statuses/500257116566085632&quot;&gt;August 15, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;script async src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Read your browsing history&amp;rdquo; isn&amp;rsquo;t an accurate description of the access
Taco has, especially when a different permission level (&amp;ldquo;history&amp;rdquo;)
exists which does grant exactly that. I&amp;rsquo;m sure that led some users to
uninstall the extension instead of upgrading and granting this
permission, so I wanted to solve the problem for other users like this
person and for other extension authors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.google.com/p/chromium/issues/detail?id=362794&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;
Chromium issue about improving permission descriptions and posted
&lt;a href=&quot;https://code.google.com/p/chromium/issues/detail?id=362794#c15&quot;&gt;a request&lt;/a&gt;
and a followup &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.google.com/p/chromium/issues/detail?id=362794#c17&quot;&gt;justification&lt;/a&gt;,
both duplicated below. The justification led to Chromium
&lt;a href=&quot;https://code.google.com/p/chromium/issues/detail?id=404334&quot;&gt;issue 404334&lt;/a&gt;
to change the description to something clearer, like &amp;ldquo;Read a list of the
20 sites you most frequently visit.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Comment #1 (&lt;a href=&quot;https://code.google.com/p/chromium/issues/detail?id=362794#c15&quot;&gt;original&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our users encountered this problem. Namely, as
&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.chrome.com/extensions/permission_warnings#warnings&quot;&gt;permission warnings&lt;/a&gt;
says, the &lt;code&gt;topSites&lt;/code&gt; permission causes users to see the same user-facing
description as the &lt;code&gt;history&lt;/code&gt; permission, even though it has far, far
less access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both permissions say it&amp;rsquo;s possible to &amp;ldquo;Read and modify your browsing
history.&amp;rdquo; While that&amp;rsquo;s accurate for the history permission, for
topSites, it should say something like &amp;ldquo;Read the 20 most frequently
visited URLs&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Read most frequently visited URLs.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(If one wanted to be really user-friendly, I could see checking for
&lt;code&gt;newtab&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;chrome_url_overrides&lt;/code&gt; and adjusting the message for that,
like &amp;ldquo;Read most frequently visited URLs (such as for new tab pages)&amp;rdquo; or
linking to a page which says same.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, end result is that right now, end users can&amp;rsquo;t tell the
difference between two permissions which should involve very different
amounts of trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Comment #2 (&lt;a href=&quot;https://code.google.com/p/chromium/issues/detail?id=362794#c17&quot;&gt;original&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for the fast reply and thoughtful comments, Mustafa. I totally
agree that none of these is universally perfect. I do think there&amp;rsquo;s 3
challenges with the current (new) topSites description:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;When interpreted by almost any user, it&amp;rsquo;s inaccurate. No user thinks
of &amp;ldquo;browsing history&amp;rdquo; as &amp;ldquo;the most frequently accessed sites,&amp;rdquo; let alone
&amp;ldquo;the sites on my new tab page.&amp;rdquo; It uses a phrase (&amp;ldquo;browsing history&amp;rdquo;)
which, while obviously not intentionally wrong, doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean what it&amp;rsquo;s
intended to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;  Here&amp;rsquo;s an example I encountered today:
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/adamsait/status/500242045701988353&quot;&gt;tweet&lt;/a&gt;. Nobody
thinks &amp;ldquo;browsing history&amp;rdquo; means &amp;ldquo;URLs of top 20 sites.&amp;rdquo; This manifests
in lower user satisfaction because users decline to use extensions
they&amp;rsquo;d actually be comfortable with.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Users can&amp;rsquo;t differentiate between 2 very different permission levels.
By conflating two very different amounts of access (&lt;code&gt;topSites&lt;/code&gt; and
&lt;code&gt;history&lt;/code&gt;) into the same single message, a user isn&amp;rsquo;t told the difference.
Many, maybe a majority of, users who would be uncomfortable granting
history would be completely comfortable granting topSites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;  In as much as the goal of the permissions system is to let users make
informed decisions, two very different amounts of access should be
described differently. (The corollary of this argument: if they aren&amp;rsquo;t
different enough to justify different descriptions, we might as well
obsolete topSites and exclusively use history. I don&amp;rsquo;t think that at
all, though!).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It deters extensions from using topSites, or would if extension authors
knew about this problem ahead of time. I just released an update to a new
tab page which started using &lt;code&gt;topSites&lt;/code&gt;
(&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tacoapp/status/500268474560946177&quot;&gt;tweet&lt;/a&gt;). If I&amp;rsquo;d
known 24 hours ago what I know now about the permission wording, I would
not have added topSites support to our extension. Because it&amp;rsquo;s so
generic, the user message is scarier than the feature justifies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Experience as a customer of Simple.com</title>
    <link href="http://troy.yort.com/experience-as-a-customer-of-simple-dot-com/"/>
		<updated>2014-05-21T15:12:54-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://troy.yort.com/experience-as-a-customer-of-simple-dot-com</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Jack Gavigan posted &lt;a href=&quot;http://jackgavigan.com/2014/04/14/disruptive-bank/&quot;&gt;What would a disruptive bank look like?&lt;/a&gt;
and Simple Finance Technology Corp. (AKA Simple.com, formerly
BankSimple) was one of the services he used as a baseline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been a customer of Simple since very close to day 1, so I posted
&lt;a href=&quot;http://jackgavigan.com/2014/04/14/disruptive-bank/#comment-1082&quot;&gt;a comment&lt;/a&gt;
with off-the-cuff notes. My comment is duplicated below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s my notes on experiences as a customer since very close to day 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Overall&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simple does almost everything I want from a basic retail bank. I felt
like they had enough access and control to try to solve many of the
problems I&amp;rsquo;d had with other banks. Without the full stack, they still
had no shortage of ways to stand out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Completeness&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I actually wanted fewer internally-maintained features than Simple
provided. For example, I didn&amp;rsquo;t use Simple&amp;rsquo;s goals at all, though I can
see from Twitter comments that some customers did. As another example,
Simple&amp;rsquo;s automatic merchant name cleanup was a minor convenience at best,
and had enough errors that I&amp;rsquo;m not sure it was worth the effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simple had basically reached maturity for a basic retail bank. Yes, there
was and is more it could do, but they&amp;rsquo;re the long tail of retail banking
features. (What would an end-to-end reinvention of a bank let them provide
that isn&amp;rsquo;t doable today? Perhaps doing less, not more, and exposing &amp;ldquo;raw&amp;rdquo;
parts of the stack for a future ZenPayroll or Balanced to consume).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Support (and paying for it..)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Support made or broke the service to a degree that I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect, even
coming from a bank where I had a personal rep. Simple&amp;rsquo;s site treats support
discussions as the first-class elements they are. The staff is responsive
and savvy. It made a huge difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know how interchange fees would cover the costs of Simple&amp;rsquo;s customer
support, let alone software development, ops, and support. Although support
was very thorough, Simple didn&amp;rsquo;t spend a lot of effort turning answers into
something that would let other customers find the answer themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of my questions were factual topics which could easily go in a FAQ:
policies, limits, service features. Obviously I&amp;rsquo;d like my bank to be
sustainable on the fees it collects, which made it somewhat frustrating when
I had to ask a question that didn&amp;rsquo;t then end up somewhere in Simple&amp;rsquo;s docs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This might be a comprehensive FAQ (yes, there&amp;rsquo;s a FAQ, no, it&amp;rsquo;s not
comprehensive), a public Discourse-style forum, or giving certain customers
edit access to the existing FAQ and having staff moderate and release the
changes. I think Simple was hoping to differentiate mostly on service, so
providing fewer human interactions didn&amp;rsquo;t really appeal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It felt like there was a decision here: either they&amp;rsquo;re a premium bank with
a monthly price, or they&amp;rsquo;re a friend-of-all consumer bank like what WaMu
tried to brand themselves as.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Oaxaca street food recommendations</title>
    <link href="http://troy.yort.com/oaxaca-street-food-recommendations/"/>
		<updated>2014-03-30T14:08:23-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://troy.yort.com/oaxaca-street-food-recommendations</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I returned from Oaxaca, I found a Chow.com thread titled &amp;ldquo;Oaxaca
for dummies.&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;d eaten at most of the sit-down restaurants mentioned in
the discussion, yet they weren&amp;rsquo;t meals I enjoyed most or remembered
most. Street food was. I wrote &lt;a href=&quot;http://chowhound.chow.com/topics/354760#8849236&quot;&gt;this comment&lt;/a&gt;
with food truck and tianguis/market meal suggestions. My comment is
duplicated below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;trying to support entrepreneurs in Oaxaca. added Tlayudas Doña Gloria to Google Maps, Flickr: &lt;a href=&quot;http://t.co/V7JZmO1nyN&quot;&gt;http://t.co/V7JZmO1nyN&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://t.co/qDbkesD2sP&quot;&gt;http://t.co/qDbkesD2sP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Troy Davis (@troyd) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/troyd/statuses/400324521082642432&quot;&gt;November 12, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;script async src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just returned from 4 months in Oaxaca. Here&amp;rsquo;s my very condensed
best-of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DESAYUNO &amp;ndash; TACOS&lt;/strong&gt;: 2 taco stands setup on the sidewalk at the far NW
corner of the Templo del Carmen Alto starting at 8:30:
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/Registro+Civil+del+Estado/@17.0673634,-96.7241585,20z&quot;&gt;Google Maps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get a tinga taco from the southern-most one (in the corner), then walk
on to the northern one on the sidewalk. If the northernmost one isn&amp;rsquo;t
there that day, get 1 tinga and 1 chorizo :&amp;ndash;) It&amp;rsquo;s actually
&lt;a href=&quot;https://foursquare.com/v/tacos-de-chorizo-del-carmen-alto/4ebd8b1b61af9815e138f31d&quot;&gt;on Foursquare&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DESAYUNO &amp;ndash; MUFFIN&lt;/strong&gt;: the Cafe Brujula on Garcia Vigil bakes berry muffins
every morning. They come out at about 9:
&lt;a href=&quot;http://cafebrujula.com/index.php?lang=en#locations&quot;&gt;Cafe Brujula&lt;/a&gt;. Most
pastries in Mexico are little more than sugar and flour. These muffins
are amazing and the venue is nice for wifi. Skip the banana loaf thing
if that&amp;rsquo;s all they have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;COMIDA &amp;ndash; TOSTADAS&lt;/strong&gt;: Tostadas at a stand about 3 meters into Parque El
Llano (off of Avenida Juarez). There are a handful of stands throughout
the park, so I&amp;rsquo;ve attached a map with an X where this one is. At least
as of this writing, it has a green awning and is run by 1 woman and
sometimes a man. They&amp;rsquo;re around every day. Recommend 1 or 2 tostadas
with tinga, tasajo, or whatever she&amp;rsquo;s got.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;COMIDA &amp;ndash; TORTA&lt;/strong&gt;: Every Friday, there&amp;rsquo;s a mercado at Parque El Llano. At
the southernmost street bordering the park, there&amp;rsquo;s a taco stand called.
Chitos Tacos or Chatos Tacos It&amp;rsquo;s across the street from 100% Natural,
facing north into the market. Get a torta Hawaiana and a taco.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CENA &amp;ndash; TLAYUDA&lt;/strong&gt;: after 8:30 or 8:45 PM (which is not late for dinner in
Oaxaca), get a tlayuda con tasajo from Cenaduría Doña Gloria: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/preview?hl=en&amp;amp;cid=12755649183580244725&quot;&gt;Google Maps&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I picked one must-have meal in Oaxaca, this is it. The food is
amazing, uniquely Oaxaqueñan, and you&amp;rsquo;re eating on her front porch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s great with friends, and if you&amp;rsquo;re so inclined, bring a beer poured
into a Coke bottle. Ask for cebollas on the side and she&amp;rsquo;ll hand you a
Tupperware of awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The map is dead-on accurate. You&amp;rsquo;ll see this sign on the sidewalk of Río
Amazonas: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/Tlayudas+Do%C3%B1a+Gloria/@17.076582,-96.723928,2a,90y,90t/data=!3m5!1e2!3m3!1shttps:%2F%2Flh6.googleusercontent.com%2F-YETy_d4SvGk%2FUoWxuvx2oxI%2FAAAAAAAAAKI%2F0uMpi484fVI%2Fs270%2Fphoto.JPG!2e4!3e12!4m2!3m1!1s0x0:0xb1052b59a2cd4af5!6m1!1e1?hl=en&quot;&gt;Cenaduría Doña Gloria&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of the streets in Xochimilco/La Cascada are dead-ends, but if
you&amp;rsquo;re lost, ask someone and they&amp;rsquo;re likely to know where she is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The walk from El Centro is really nice, too, and leads past where
Mercado El Pochote happens every Friday and Saturday:
&lt;a href=&quot;http://oaxaca-chapulines.blogspot.com/2012/01/mercado-el-pochote.html&quot;&gt;El Pochote&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Taco: Basecamp to Zendesk, all your tasks on one place</title>
    <link href="http://troy.yort.com/taco-basecamp-to-zendesk/"/>
		<updated>2013-06-22T16:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://troy.yort.com/taco-basecamp-to-zendesk</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My take on productivity, &lt;a href=&quot;http://tacoapp.com/&quot;&gt;Taco&lt;/a&gt;, is now on Kickstarter: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/tacoapp/taco-basecamp-to-zendesk-all-your-tasks-in-one-pla&quot;&gt;Taco: Basecamp to Zendesk, all your tasks in one place&lt;/a&gt;. As I told friends:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Most of you know I run Papertrail and that it takes all of my time
and then some. I&amp;rsquo;ve stayed sane because of a unique Web app that I&amp;rsquo;ve
been prototyping and using daily for 23 months.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week that secret weapon took on a life of its own when Taco launched &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/tacoapp/taco-basecamp-to-zendesk-all-your-tasks-in-one-pla&quot;&gt;on Kickstarter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the creator of Rails took notice:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nice kickstarter for a unified todolist that brings content together from Basecamp, Github, Google, and others: &lt;a href=&quot;http://t.co/To88EwsXh6&quot;&gt;http://t.co/To88EwsXh6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; DHH (@dhh) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dhh/statuses/347280173999202304&quot;&gt;June 19, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;script async src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Take a look and see whether it fits the way you work. I look forward to bringing you the same fine productivity I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed for 2 years.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>The elements of a great customer support reply</title>
    <link href="http://troy.yort.com/the-elements-of-a-great-customer-support-reply/"/>
		<updated>2013-04-03T15:39:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://troy.yort.com/the-elements-of-a-great-customer-support-reply</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I wrote a comment reply on &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&quot;http://supportops.co/a-better-feature-request-email/#comment-170&quot;&gt;A Better Feature Request Email&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; (at &lt;a href=&quot;http://supportops.co&quot;&gt;SupportOps&lt;/a&gt;) that covers the elements which I think go into a great customer support reply. I also rewrote an example reply from the blog post. My comment is reposted below or you can read &lt;a href=&quot;http://supportops.co/a-better-feature-request-email/#comment-170&quot;&gt;the thread&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your reply is absolute gold. I don’t have much to add. I completely agree it’s all about being authentic, whatever authentic is. I particularly love the &amp;ldquo;You company should be customer inspired not customer driven.&amp;rdquo; I can’t imagine any better way to state it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My responses boil down to 3 things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;demonstrating that I understand what the user asked for, whether it’s by restating it in my own words or talking through the pros and cons of what they propose.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;either clarifying what they’re asking for and why (the back story that led to needing it) or when none is needed needed (like because the request stands alone or we’ve already thought about it), sharing our thought process about it rather than just an answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; This is by far the most important part because it means the user is a peer in the process. They should have the opportunity to explain why I’m (we’re) wrong, just like a co-worker of mine would. if I’m suggesting some other way to solve the same problem, it forces me to talk through (justify) its pros and cons clearly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;providing a clear resolution, whether it’s that nothing will be done, that’s the use is on our radar and I see the value but it’s not likely to happen anytime soon, or that we love it enough that it’s likely really soon. (We don’t do a roadmap or anything like that, and I think they – and committing to them – do more damage than good.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Now I need to put my keystrokes where my mouth is. For a new user with whom I’ve never interacted, I might write something like the reply below. I made up the facts to show a range of responses, though I may only have one. For questions which I’d answered before, the meat would be based on an existing reply. I’d adapt it to the recipient’s apparent interest – is it more &amp;ldquo;I want..&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;You guys should..&amp;rdquo; – and technical ability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hi James,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for trying SupportOps and moreover, for caring enough about it to spend the time to send this suggestion. I appreciate it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s not a way to login with Facebook or Twitter credentials. I can understand why you’d want to, though, especially if you’ve standardized on one of them as your login service at other sites. Right now I have so many passwords that Keychain or LastPass are the only way to keep them all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do one thing that’s made logging in way less tedious for me: SupportOps’ login time (session duration) is 4 weeks. If you’ve checked “Keep me logged in,” you should not see a login prompt more than once a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on your email, I think we’ll improve it by resetting the timer on every page view. I know that yet another password isn’t great, but at least you’d almost never see a login prompt. I can’t commit to it, so I’ll let you know if and when that goes live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstractly, I’d like to add third-party authentication. would probably be what we used, since it’s most related to SupportOps. That said, basically all of our dev resources are going into the core service right now. might be used by 20% of SupportCo users, and we’re not done with big changes that improve the service for almost everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I might also write: “One thing I’ve learned is that aside from the actual integration, providing a great user flow with third-party services is a lot harder than it seems. &lt;a href=&quot;http://viget.com/extend/facebook-connect-ux-challenges&quot;&gt;http://viget.com/extend/facebook-connect-ux-challenges&lt;/a&gt; explains more. I think maintaining a great UX would mean we’d need to invest the time to get it right.” -Troy)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d welcome feedback here, and thanks again for giving me the chance to talk through our current thinking. if you have any other questions, just let me know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Troy&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Why Web apps suck at invoices (and vice versa)</title>
    <link href="http://troy.yort.com/why-web-apps-suck-at-invoices-and-vice-versa/"/>
		<updated>2012-09-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://troy.yort.com/why-web-apps-suck-at-invoices-and-vice-versa</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On the &lt;a href=&quot;https://scoutapp.com/&quot;&gt;Scout&lt;/a&gt; support &lt;a href=&quot;https://groups.google.com/group/scoutapp&quot;&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt;, a prospective customer asked to receive an invoice instead of the typical credit card payment. I have some unique experience with that, so I posted the comment below as food for thought (see &lt;a href=&quot;https://groups.google.com/group/scoutapp/browse_thread/thread/660f3ade8bcd5928/e3dce7fb91a7d1b2?#e3dce7fb91a7d1b2&quot;&gt;thread&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is &amp;ldquo;Why Web apps suck at invoices&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Why invoices suck for Web apps,&amp;rdquo; all rolled into one. Next time someone requests an invoice, send them here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subject: invoice billing (was: Re: Fees for Rails Apps..)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not affiliated with Scout except as a customer, but I run an unrelated subscription Web service that sells to businesses and I&amp;rsquo;m occasionally asked the same question. It sounds like a really simple request, so I can understand the frustration at not being able to accommodate it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to add some color about how challenging it is to provide invoices. I&amp;rsquo;m speaking only about my experience, not Scout&amp;rsquo;s. Here&amp;rsquo;s why this is often a much bigger pain than it looks like, and is often actually a disadvantage to both parties:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Everything is a one-off. Almost everyone who wants an invoice also needs some other customization: the delivery process, the followup, the formatting (&amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re in Germany and our government requires you to tell us who we are&amp;rdquo;), whatever. Aside from tracking those one-offs, they makes it harder to solve or automate the other issues below. Which leads me to..&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Everything requires a human. If you don&amp;rsquo;t pay, a human has to email you, and it will almost never be worth the time to automate that process (especially in light of customer-specific processes above). Even something as simple as a credit becomes a time sink. A human needs to figure out how much is due (best case, transferring the amount from a summary email that a developer had to implement; worst case, calculating it manually); figure out how to get you the money (edit a future invoice, reissue an existing invoice, or cut you a check); deliver that credit, probably to someone in accounting who doesn&amp;rsquo;t know anything about what&amp;rsquo;s being purchased; process the payment; and come back a few weeks later to verify it was paid.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Someone has to go to the PO Box and then to the bank, and it needs to happen often enough that you don&amp;rsquo;t look like an idiot for depositing a 2 month old check.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reconciliation is harder. Accounting typically needs an entry for every individual customer payment, rather than one per day per credit card or however other transactions are handled.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having an elastic payment method is really awesome, and our service and many others bake that assumption into our UX decisions and business processes. By &amp;ldquo;elastic&amp;rdquo; I mean that the amount isn&amp;rsquo;t set in stone a month before the service is provided. What should happen if you add a new host that you didn&amp;rsquo;t plan for? Does the vendor extend credit, or do they issue an invoice with a pro-rated line item and make you wait until it&amp;rsquo;s paid? How about 100 new hosts? Before long, the customer is predicting and committing to a certain amount of usage, quite possibly just to make billing simpler, and we&amp;rsquo;ve undone 15 years of software-as-a-service progress.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;All of this distracts from making the product better. Whether a company has 2 people or 100, the resources are finite, and at some level any other work is in place of product improvements. No Web service will ever be great at invoicing, most will never be good at it, and not one will ever enjoy it. That &amp;ldquo;morale debt&amp;rdquo; accumulates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The overhead will eventually be reflected in prices, and it&amp;rsquo;s way higher than the ~3% for credit cards. This thread started as a question about fees. One reason that Scout is such a good value is that their decisions mostly optimize for practical value. Building off its usage-based fees, would you be willing to pay a $25/invoice fee, and/or have a $500/invoice minimum? From my own experience, that&amp;rsquo;s the absolute minimum it takes to make this practical, and I&amp;rsquo;m probably still way too low.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;None of this is rocket science, it just takes time, and that&amp;rsquo;s why invoices suck for typical business subscription services. I consider it a positive that Scout is savvy enough to focus on what they&amp;rsquo;re good at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, a potential solution: get a company card that&amp;rsquo;s only used for recurring purchases like this. You&amp;rsquo;re freed from monthly employee expense reports and accounting gains authoritative information about the transaction, since it&amp;rsquo;s essentially their card.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Examining borrower privacy in peer-to-peer lending</title>
    <link href="http://troy.yort.com/borrower-privacy-in-peer-to-peer-lending/"/>
		<updated>2012-08-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://troy.yort.com/borrower-privacy-in-peer-to-peer-lending</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I just &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/troyd/status/238085893280395264&quot;&gt;noticed&lt;/a&gt; that the sales reports published by &lt;a href=&quot;http://lendingclub.com/&quot;&gt;Lending Club&lt;/a&gt; contain enough personally-identifiable information (PII) to be, well, personally-identifiable. Per the instructions on their &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lendingclub.com/public/privacy-policy.action&quot;&gt;privacy policy&lt;/a&gt;, I emailed this to the privacy role account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a point of reference, here&amp;rsquo;s the equivalent &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.prosper.com/prospectus/&quot;&gt;prospectuses&lt;/a&gt; and an example &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.prosper.com/published/sec/sales/2012/sales_20120820-0900.htm&quot;&gt;sales report&lt;/a&gt; from Prosper. Prosper doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to publicly disclose a borrower&amp;rsquo;s employer or city, only an job category and a state. Prosper&amp;rsquo;s freeform loan descriptions are more detailed and the borrower sometimes refers to a location, but the aggregate information is still not generally enough to identify the borrower, and never is unless the borrower over-discloses. I am not affiliated with either service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the email to Lending Club (August 21, 2012) and their reply (September 6, 2012):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi all,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a prospective lender and I just skimmed the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lendingclub.com/info/prospectus.action&quot;&gt;prospectuses&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lendingclub.com/info/sales-reports.action&quot;&gt;sales report&lt;/a&gt; filings, then I read them, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lendingclub.com/public/privacy-policy.action&quot;&gt;privacy policy&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lendingclub.com/kb/index.php?CategoryID=19&quot;&gt;privacy section&lt;/a&gt; of Lending Club&amp;rsquo;s knowledge base in more detail. The privacy policy contains two material discrepancies, one of which I believe is substantial. I explain the discrepancies in detail below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe the fix is relatively simple: the new borrower signup process, the privacy policy, and the knowledge base privacy section should all contain visible, obvious links to the sales reports. Right now they&amp;rsquo;re buried, and the privacy policy spends lots of words to (incompletely) describe how much will be disclosed. The borrower should be shown the actual information which will be disclosed about them, using the existing sales reports as an example. I believe this description explains the disclosure much more clearly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;If your loan is funded, Lending Club must publicly disclose certain information about you as part of public SEC filings. This includes employer, year hired, city, income, loan reason, and credit information. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lendingclub.com/info/sales-reports.action&quot;&gt;Click here to see examples of Lending Club loan disclosures&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m spending the time to write all of this down because I want to see peer-to-peer lending and Lending Club succeed, so please let me know if I can clarify anything here. Here&amp;rsquo;s more details about the 2 discrepancies:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The information disclosed about borrowers in sales reports is enough to identify many of them individually. Although the information doesn&amp;rsquo;t contain a real name, the privacy policy states:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Personal but not personally identifiable information about borrowers is contained in loan listings that can be viewed by all users and is filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission and as such is made publicly available.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt; This is inaccurate. Using the information on Lending Club&amp;rsquo;s sales reports, I could personally identify many individual borrowers, and take an educated guess about many more. In some cases this would take a bit of existing information, such as from discovering a loan request from a co-worker based on their listed employer. I can almost guarantee that another employee of Friendship Public Charter School, Reis Law, pair Networks, Fundly, and many other small- and mid-size employers listed on the 2012-08-21 sales report could name the borrower using only information from the report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; In other cases, the combination of employer, year hired, city, income, and freeform text description is enough for a stranger to identify them using relatively simple Google, LinkedIn, or Facebook searches. For many companies, the combination of those fields is unique throughout the whole company. It&amp;rsquo;s often very unique, like because only a few people were hired in a given year. Also, the &amp;ldquo;Earliest credit line&amp;rdquo; field is often a reasonable proxy for the borrower&amp;rsquo;s age, and is at least a minimum age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; In those cases, a single external corroboration such as a LinkedIn job announcement, a title transfer on BlockShopper, or a Facebook photo posted to the company&amp;rsquo;s page could be enough to attach a name.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The credit score information is both public and disclosed alongside other information which is personally identifiable. The data disclosure section says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Qualified Lending Club investors will also see certain credit data collected from or calculated based on your credit bureau file. It is necessary to allow prospective investors to see this information as they evaluate your loan request. The information displayed to investors includes a credit profile section and a credit history section. As noted above, this information is also contained anonymously in loan data files available on the statistics page.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt; It goes on to define the fields disclosed as part of the credit profile and the credit history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; It doesn&amp;rsquo;t say that the credit information is disclosed alongside lots of other personal data. Even when that information is not enough to be personally-identifiable (discrepancy #1 above), it&amp;rsquo;s public and visible to anyone. It&amp;rsquo;s not visible only to &amp;ldquo;Qualified Lending Club investors,&amp;rdquo; and perhaps more importantly, the disclosure is not on a loan-by-loan basis. In reading the paragraph above, I would interpret it to say that my information will be temporarily disclosed to all qualified lenders (prospective investors) while my loan is being funded, then will be only shown to those lenders who actually funded my loan. That isn&amp;rsquo;t the case.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Thanks,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Troy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reply from Mark D&amp;#8217;Arrigo, Associate Counsel, Lending Club:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Davis:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your email regarding the protection of personally identifiable information on the Lending Club website.  Lending Club takes consumer privacy seriously and has implemented procedures and policies designed to protect consumer information.  We appreciate your detailed feedback and have discussed your suggestions regarding our Privacy Policy and disclosures to members.  However, we believe that our Privacy Policy is consistent and does not contain material discrepancies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of our consumer privacy efforts, Lending Club informs applicants regarding the type of information that will be disclosed to the public both in the Privacy Policy itself and throughout the application via the use of tool tips, a pop-up that notifies the applicant that information placed into certain fields is made available to the public.  We also review loan titles and free-form answers provided by applicants in an attempt to limit the exposure of personally identifiable information that applicants may provide outside the marked application fields.  Lastly, credit information is only available for viewing by Lending Club members and not available to non-members merely perusing the site.  As you noted, from the information available on our site, members such as yourself can view the information about borrowers that Lending Club must file with the Securities and Exchange Commission.  We do not agree, however, that this constitutes &amp;ldquo;personally identifiable&amp;rdquo; information.  Your letter indicates that you were only able to take an &amp;ldquo;educated guess&amp;rdquo; about the identity of some borrowers using information you gathered from other sources.  The fact that certain limited information regarding borrowers is viewable through the Lending Club website &amp;mdash; which, again, Lending Club flags as publicly disclosed in the application itself and in our Privacy Policy &amp;mdash; and that similar information may also be available through external sources that contain additional information does not, in our view, indicate that Lending Club displays personally identifiable information or that our Privacy Policy contains material discrepancies.  We also do not believe that the manner in which certain personal information is presented on the website is inconsistent with our Privacy Policy or other consumer protection initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although we disagree with your conclusions and interpretations, we appreciate your email and thank you for your feedback.  We periodically review our consumer privacy policies and processes and will take your specific suggestions under consideration as part of that review process.  Thank you very much for your time and your interest in Lending Club.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sincerely yours,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mark D&amp;#8217;Arrigo&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Associate Counsel&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>A few days with the SlimFold Tyvek Wallet</title>
    <link href="http://troy.yort.com/a-few-days-with-the-slimfold-tyvek-wallet/"/>
		<updated>2012-08-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://troy.yort.com/a-few-days-with-the-slimfold-tyvek-wallet</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Update (January 19, 2014): After 2 Slimfolds, I&amp;rsquo;m still completely satisfied. I ordered a Slimfold Micro today. Read on for my initial experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href=&quot;http://slimfoldwallet.com/&quot;&gt;SlimFold Wallet&lt;/a&gt; arrived in Bangkok. Here&amp;rsquo;s a photo of mine when loaded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.yort.com/blog/slimfold-tyvek-wallet-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Photo of SlimFold Tyvek Wallet in use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After five days &amp;ndash; and two walks through monsoonal downpours &amp;ndash; I highly recommend it. A few smart UX choices make all the difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each section actually holds two cards. In the photo, you can see both card pockets on one of the sections. There&amp;rsquo;s two more sections (four pockets) inside. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t try to make a statement about how much crap I should carry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cards are held firmly because the Tyvek isn&amp;rsquo;t pre-streched. Each pocket retains whatever capacity you stretch it to. (My tendency to RTFM/Skim TFM paid off here: the instructions warn not to ever stuff two cards into one pocket.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;They chose a good compromise between thickness, capacity, and physical size. It&amp;rsquo;s slightly larger than a typical trifold, and in return, can hold 10 cards and still stay hipster thin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ID pocket is secured by a folding tab, and more remarkably, it actually stays closed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The creator notes that he made and tested over 100 prototypes, and it shows. It&amp;rsquo;s available in Plutonian Gray, Steal Me Orange, and now Everyone Asks For It Black.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Cost analysis of King County Bike Share Business Plan</title>
    <link href="http://troy.yort.com/cost-analysis-of-king-county-bike-share-busin/"/>
		<updated>2012-08-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://troy.yort.com/cost-analysis-of-king-county-bike-share-busin</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I posted &lt;a href=&quot;http://seattlebikeblog.com/2012/08/09/the-plan-for-puget-sound-bike-share/#comment-168712&quot;&gt;a comment&lt;/a&gt; on this Seattle Bike Blog &lt;a href=&quot;http://seattlebikeblog.com/2012/08/09/the-plan-for-puget-sound-bike-share/&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; with a basic cost analysis of the King County Bike Share Business Plan (&lt;a href=&quot;http://pugetsoundbikeshare.org/&quot;&gt;site&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://pugetsoundbikeshare.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/KCBS_Business_Plan_FINAL.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;). This is the text of my comment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At scale, the project forecasts 2200 bikes supported by an annual operating (not build out) cost of $4.6 million. That&amp;rsquo;s $2090/bike. It forecasts 2.68 million trips per year at an average of 2 miles/trip. If those numbers are accurate, a trip would cost $1.72. A mile, $0.86.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t have a strong reaction to those costs. I would gladly pay $2/trip myself as an entirely usage-based fee. The forecasted cost is in line with Metro and Sound Transit fares. While it&amp;rsquo;s lower than their costs per boarding (for Metro, $3.70 in 2008; &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/King_County_Metro#Operating_Costs&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;), the shorter, denser routes are much cheaper to deliver than the system-wide average.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The data to compare route-level stats doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist. Shorter, denser routes are the closest comparables to phase 1. However, one could see bike sharing allowing the last mile of trips that would have otherwise been taken by car (and instead use bus or train). Not enough data to know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My own conclusion: the costs are definitely &amp;ldquo;in the zone&amp;rdquo; for transit and might be a little cheaper than existing options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crucially, the total cost is incredibly small compared to any other transit implementation, and thereby, much lower risk. As a point of reference, Metro received $37.5 million to add 2 RapidRide Bus Rapid Transit (BRT) routes (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dot.gov/affairs/2012/fta3812.html&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;). Even excluding all other revenue sources, the total build out costs of all phases are equivalent to one BRT route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As another perspective, the 4.3 mile Northgate light rail extension has a lifetime budget of $2.1 billion (70x-100x more than the total 5 year projected cost), and the South Lake Union Streetcar was $56.4 million (&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/South_Lake_Union_Streetcar&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t mean to provide these as comparables. For me, the lower cost just means the barrier for my endorsement is much lower. In urban transit, $20 million is an experiment. In this case, the &amp;ldquo;experiment&amp;rdquo; happens to fund the whole system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;relies on internally-created usage forecasts. While the forecasted 2.4 trips/bike in year 1 is within the range seen in other cities, that range is very broad (0.9 to 3.7). As you&amp;rsquo;d expect of a transit system, usage is the key to a low cost per trip.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;ignores the $14.4 million in build out expenses because they do seem to be one-time (stations) or long depreciation (vending machines), and because the report notes &amp;ldquo;presenting sponsorship is expected to cover all but $2.15 [of] .. $14.4 million.&amp;rdquo; The unfunded 2.15 million is not a material impact.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Source: King County &lt;a href=&quot;http://pugetsoundbikeshare.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/KCBS_Business_Plan_FINAL.pdf&quot;&gt;Bike Share Business Plan&lt;/a&gt; (2012-01-27), pages 26-27, 36.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Making 2-factor authentication grow faster than linear</title>
    <link href="http://troy.yort.com/making-2-factor-authentication-viral/"/>
		<updated>2012-07-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://troy.yort.com/making-2-factor-authentication-viral</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m doing what I can to spread the gospel of 2-factor authentication. My hope is that it will be adopted at a faster-than-linear rate, ideally much faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2FA isn&amp;rsquo;t a silver bullet, but it&amp;rsquo;s a gigantic improvement for relatively little effort. The elements that prevented mainstream adoption &amp;ndash; key fobs, constantly re-entering keys &amp;ndash; are not present in modern implementations like Google&amp;rsquo;s. With most of the usability tradeoffs eliminated, we&amp;rsquo;re left with a fairly typical sales problem (and of course, more operators implementing Google&amp;rsquo;s 2FA or an equally elegant alternative).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my part, &amp;ldquo;doing what I can&amp;rdquo; means:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;requiring 2FA on systems I maintain, at least where SSH keys aren&amp;rsquo;t practical or aren&amp;rsquo;t sufficient&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;sharing my success stories, especially how I solved common objections to 2FA (it&amp;rsquo;s annoying to use; I only have a few users; it&amp;rsquo;s a pain to setup)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;helping others find accurate, deep descriptions of current threats (like &lt;a href=&quot;http://krebsonsecurity.com/&quot;&gt;Krebs on Security&lt;/a&gt;) so they treat malware and botnets (and thus keystroke logging) as an endemic threat&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I think with enough satisfied users as advocates, 2FA could grow exponentially for a while (albeit with a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wolframalpha.com/input/?i=1.03%5Ex&quot;&gt;tiny base&lt;/a&gt; today). Google has basically turned 2FA into an impulse decision with a simple pitch: &amp;ldquo;Have 5 minutes? Use wifi hotspots? Protect your email from hackers (free).&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;d settle for &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Logistic_function&quot;&gt;logistic growth&lt;/a&gt; up to something short of 100% adoption, though I&amp;rsquo;m not sure a hard &lt;a href=&quot;http://20bits.com/article/three-myths-of-viral-growth&quot;&gt;carrying capacity&lt;/a&gt; exists. Future incremental usability improvements should make it palatable for more people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sales starts with awareness: that it exists, that it&amp;rsquo;s already being used by seemingly-sane people to solve similar problems (indeed, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_proof&quot;&gt;social proof&lt;/a&gt;), and that it stands up to daily production use. Here&amp;rsquo;s an email that I sent to the Seattle Internet Exchange &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.seattleix.net/faq.htm&quot;&gt;chat&lt;/a&gt; mailing list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To: chat@&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Passing this on in case anyone else could use flexible, painless, free 2-factor auth for servers and network devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been testing Google&amp;rsquo;s 2-factor authentication via a &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/google-authenticator/wiki/PamModuleInstructions&quot;&gt;PAM&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s working beautifully. Google has iOS, Android, and Blackberry one-time password &lt;a href=&quot;http://support.google.com/accounts/bin/answer.py?hl=en&amp;amp;amp;answer=1066447&quot;&gt;apps&lt;/a&gt;. Ubuntu and Debian package the module as libpam-google-authenticator. During setup, it spits out the key as an ASCII QR code that the mobile apps read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t tried having RADIUS use google-authenticator&amp;rsquo;s PAM, but it seems like it would work. Other people talk about using it: &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/google-authenticator/issues/detail?id=145&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, SSH with challenge/response prompts for the challenge first (with a prompt of its own), but PAM supports a &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/google-authenticator/issues/detail?id=39&quot;&gt;concatenated mode&lt;/a&gt; where the OTP is prepended to the static secret. This should play well with network devices that present a single password prompt. Google&amp;rsquo;s module validates the OTP, then passes the secret on to the next module as usual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, SSH authorized keys still work (assuming the SSH config permits them), so you can decide how annoying one-time passwords will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, worth noting that this setup is completely separate from having a Google account. An account isn&amp;rsquo;t required. This setup uses Google&amp;rsquo;s mobile app implementation of &lt;a href=&quot;http://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc6238&quot;&gt;time-based one-time passwords&lt;/a&gt;, the app&amp;rsquo;s ability to import your own key(s), and a PAM that they maintain, all of which are &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/google-authenticator/source/browse&quot;&gt;OSS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Answering &#8220;What one thing should Apple work on?&#8221;</title>
    <link href="http://troy.yort.com/answering-what-one-thing-should-apple-work-on/"/>
		<updated>2012-05-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://troy.yort.com/answering-what-one-thing-should-apple-work-on</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Apple market research surveys often end with a wonderfully engaging question: what one thing should Apple work on? Here&amp;rsquo;s my most recent answer (submitted on May 20, 2012).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m an incredibly satisfied Apple customer. If I could come up with a glaring problem, it would be below. Although this is my #1 suggestion, in absolute terms it hardly ranks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I mentioned &amp;ldquo;non-Apple apps&amp;rdquo; because other survey questions differentiated between Apple and third-party apps. It isn&amp;rsquo;t how I categorize them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is an unedited Web form submission, not an essay.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;As an aside, this question is infinitely more useful than the question that most short surveys ask, &amp;ldquo;Would you recommend us to someone else?&amp;rdquo; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Net_Promoter&quot;&gt;Net Promoter&lt;/a&gt; Score).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Question: What one thing should Apple work on?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Short&lt;/strong&gt;: Use Apple resources to help encourage the next 10 Omni Groups and the next 10 Instapapers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Long&lt;/strong&gt;: A lot of my time is spent using non-Apple apps, which is completely fine, but makes me wonder how many opportunities exist for Apple to reach out to authors of popular niche or &amp;ldquo;power user&amp;rdquo; apps &amp;ndash; Simplenote, Notational Velocity, Sublime Text, iTerm, TextMate, WindowShade X, and many more &amp;ndash; and find ways to either make their lives easier as ISVs, or make the power of those apps available to more users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of these ISV apps have mainstream potential, and those that don&amp;rsquo;t still have tons more appeal beyond the distribution they get today (people actively seeking them out). Apple&amp;rsquo;s decision to create Reading List rather than work with Instapaper made its NIH perspective really obvious: even an amazing product from one of the most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple has tons of happy fanboy ISVs who are eager (thrilled!) to adapt or even design their strategies around Apple&amp;rsquo;s. There&amp;rsquo;s zero risk of being abandoned by ISVs or partners due to lack of relevance, like happened with CodeWarrior and nearly with Office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The very real risk is not making the most of the fanboys that Apple has, or tempering their excitement until they recede from True Fans to merely satisfied users. Apple has done an amazing job of creating opportunities for commercial success with the iOS and Mac App Stores, but they&amp;rsquo;ve been very hands-off, fairly self-serving (with the well-jusified 30% fee), and rarely backed by actual Apple resources, strategic decisions (&amp;ldquo;wow, users love Instapaper, it&amp;rsquo;s cheap, the author is as committed as anyone can ever be to the platform &amp;mdash; let&amp;rsquo;s bundle Instapaper&amp;rdquo;) or, well, passion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(The best counterexample I can think of is actually Apple&amp;rsquo;s iPhone TV commercials, and they&amp;rsquo;re only counterexamples in that they show just how big of an impact Apple can have when it uses strategic resources to help ISVs.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my challenge, my wish, is that in a few years I can name 9 more thriving OS X ISVs instead of just Omni Group. It&amp;rsquo;s that I can iOS app authors whose businesses have thrived not just because of the App Store, but because Apple took an interest in their businesses and identified ways to bring their products to more people, improve the integration, or just make their lives easier as ISVs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Obligatory disclaimer: I&amp;rsquo;m not an ISV and I don&amp;rsquo;t have a horse in this race. My only hat is as a user.)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Towards a transparent wireless carrier customer dashboard</title>
    <link href="http://troy.yort.com/towards-a-transparent-wireless-carrier-custom/"/>
		<updated>2011-09-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://troy.yort.com/towards-a-transparent-wireless-carrier-custom</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the mobile carrier customer dashboard that I want (or see as a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/yortlabs/sets/72157627583858838/&quot;&gt;Flickr set&lt;/a&gt;). The annotations tell the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m hoping that at least one of Sprint, T-Mobile, Verizon, or AT&amp;amp;T will eventually realize that transparency is a differentiator (if only because they run out of other ways to stand out). Most of these dashboard elements are possible with existing data that carriers already collect, and in some cases already have in this form for internal use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This shows two variations on the same dashboard landing page.&amp;nbsp;Click for larger versions to read the annotations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.yort.com/blog/wireless-dashboard-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Wireless dashboard sketch #1&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.yort.com/blog/wireless-dashboard-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Wireless dashboard sketch #2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Same wireframes as a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/yortlabs/sets/72157627583858838/&quot;&gt;Flickr set&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>One-click Canon PIXMA MX870 scanning in OS X</title>
    <link href="http://troy.yort.com/one-click-canon-pixma-mx870-scanning-in-os-x/"/>
		<updated>2011-08-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://troy.yort.com/one-click-canon-pixma-mx870-scanning-in-os-x</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Problem: Canon PIXMA MX870 says &amp;ldquo;Set the PC to start scanning&amp;rdquo; when the &amp;ldquo;Black&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Color&amp;rdquo; scan start buttons are pressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Solution: How I enabled one-button scanning&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Install most of the OS X drivers and software from &lt;a href=&quot;http://usa.canon.com/cusa/consumer/products/printers_multifunction/office_all_in_one_inkjet_printers/pixma_mx870#DriversAndSoftware&quot;&gt;canon.com&lt;/a&gt;. I think I installed all of the drivers, or at least ran their downloaded installers. As of this writing, that&amp;rsquo;s ICA Driver, CUPS Driver, Scanner Driver, Mini Master Setup. I also installed MP Navigator and IJ Network Tool from the software downloads. Reboot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;After installing the &amp;ldquo;Canon IJ Network Scanner Selector,&amp;rdquo; a printer/scanner icon should appear in the dock. The installer sets up the app to run at startup, which I left enabled. The dock dropdown &amp;ldquo;Scan images using the operations panel of the scanner&amp;rdquo; option is enabled. The scanner MAC address is listed and selected in &amp;ldquo;Open Settings&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://images.yort.com/blog/canon-pixma-mx870-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://images.yort.com/blog/canon-pixma-mx870-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Run MP Navigator (3.1) and on the main menu, there&amp;rsquo;s an option in the upper right &amp;ldquo;One-click.&amp;rdquo; Mouseover it and a different menu will be shown, including a &amp;ldquo;Start scanning by clicking the button&amp;rdquo; checkbox. This was not the default. I wish I was making this up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://images.yort.com/blog/canon-pixma-mx870-3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;On that MP Navigator One-click screen, click Preferences. Note that you may have 2 entries under &amp;ldquo;Product Name&amp;rdquo; (&amp;ldquo;MX870 Series&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;MX870 Series (Network: &lt;Your MAC&gt;).&amp;rdquo; I disabled &amp;ldquo;Compress scanned images when transferring&amp;rdquo; for both product names. On the Scanner Button Settings screen, I changed the paths under &amp;ldquo;Save to PC&amp;rdquo; but didn&amp;rsquo;t make any other changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://images.yort.com/blog/canon-pixma-mx870-4.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://images.yort.com/blog/canon-pixma-mx870-5.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;After making these changes, I was still seeing &amp;ldquo;Set the PC to start scanning&amp;rdquo; when I tried to scan. I shut down MP Navigator and restarted the printer (with the PC on) and it started auto-scanning. I didn&amp;rsquo;t restart the PC except after step 1. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure whether the problem was a one-time issue because the settings changed or a recurring one with the order that they were originally powered on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;My scanner LCD options (Document or Photo, DPI) are interpreted correctly. Scanning PDFs from the document feeder and bitmap images from the platen both work. Bitmaps from the ADF are not supported (the scanner says to use the platen). I haven&amp;rsquo;t tried PDFs from the platen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tested with: OS X 10.6.8, Canon IJ Network Scanner Selector 4.5.0, MP Navigator EX 3.1.3, MX870 driver 10.51.1.0.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the printer options from System Preferences. I didn&amp;rsquo;t make any changes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.yort.com/blog/canon-pixma-mx870-6.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
</feed>
